(ﾊﾞﾊﾑｰﾄ)グオォーー！
ドシュー！
RAGE OF BAHAMUT
ドカン ドカン
ドカン ドカン…
ドカーン！
(兵士)退避！
(兵士)退避！ 船を離れろ～！
Retreat! Retreat! Abandon ship!
ドカーン！
(ﾊﾟﾝ屋)こりゃダメかもな…｡
We might be done for.
ああっ
うちの辺りが爆発したよ 今｡
Oh, no, that explosion was right near our home!
≪ドシュー！
(一同)ああっ！
Oh, no...
やべぇ… 逃げろ！
Run!
ドカーン！
(一同)ああっ！
No, Kaisar...
(ﾘﾀ)ちょっと あ… あんた➡
Just hold on!
しっかりしなさいよ！
へ… 陛下…｡
Your Highness...
ぐっ… ぐはっ！ ごほっ ごほっ｡
(ﾘﾀ)カイザル！
Kaisar!
-Death...
-What?
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)し…｡
(ﾘﾀ)何？
Death...
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)真の…➡
It's so peaceful...
安寧を…｡
No!
クゥー クゥ…
(ﾆｰﾅ･ﾄﾞﾗﾝｺﾞ)
よかった ヒッポ 無事で｡
Oh, Hippo, I'm so glad you're okay.
≪ドカーン！
≪(ﾊﾞﾊﾑｰﾄ)グオォーー！
I'm going to help the others.
(父･回想)
((みんなを助けに行ってくる))
ヒッポ… 師匠たちをよろしくね｡
Hippo.
Please take care of Master and the others.
(ﾌｧﾊﾞﾛ･ﾚｵｰﾈ)ニーナ…｡
あっ｡
Nina...
師匠 大丈夫？
Master! Are you okay?
俺は大丈夫だ｡ くっ…｡
Don't worry about me.
Just listen.
だから 聞け｡
１０年前
バハムートの野郎が現れたとき➡
Ten years ago,
when Bahamut appeared,
俺は…｡
I...
守ると約束した女の命を諦めて➡
I sacrificed the life of a girl
that I promised to protect
and chose this world.
この世界を選んだ｡
Nina...
ニーナ➡
お前は 何を選ぶ？
Which will you choose?
あの人！
Him!
Go get them, Nina.
行ってこい ニーナ｡
ドカーン！
You don't need to worry about
what will happen to the world.
世界がどうなろうと そんなもん
お前が考える必要なんてねぇ｡
Just do us all a favor
あの野郎に➡
ぶちかましてやれ～‼
and tear that thing to shreds!
ドカーン！
グオォーー！
After the beast is taken down
(ｼｬﾘｵｽ17世)あれを始末して
まだ 余が生きていたのなら➡
and I am still alive,
この命 お前たちの
好きにしてもらってかまわない｡
then you can do as you please with my life.
Your Majesty!
(ｼｬﾌﾞﾛﾙ)陛下 ご武運を｡
May fortune smile upon you.
ふっ 心にもないことを｡
You don't even mean that.
Take off at the moment
when His Majesty reaches Dromos!
陛下が ドロモスに到達したら
すぐに離脱しろ！
ドシュー！
ドォーン！
(ｹﾙﾍﾞﾛｽ)うっ！ もう もたないよ｡
I can't hold on!
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)
全軍 守りに集中するのです｡
All forces, focus on defense!
(ﾙｼﾌｪﾙ)持ちこたえるんだ！
We will endure!
ドシュー！
Nina!
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)ニーナ！
このときを待っていた｡
This is the moment I've been waiting for.
ぐっ！ なぜ来た!?
Why are you here?
-Stop!
-No!
やめろ！
やめない！
あなたが命をささげるなら➡
If you're going to offer up your life,
then I will too!
私も一緒にささげる！
There's no need for you to die as well.
お前まで死ぬ必要はない｡
私は諦めない｡
I'm not giving up!
Not on my own life.
私が生きることも
あなたが生きることも➡
And not on yours either.
I'm not giving up on us!
絶対に諦めない！
(ﾊﾞﾊﾑｰﾄ)グオォーー！
ビシュー！
ドシュー！
ドォーーン‼
(ﾊﾞﾊﾑｰﾄ)グオォーーー‼
アーミラ…｡
Amira...
し… 死んだのか？
Is it dead?
We're saved.
助かった…
俺たちは助かったんだ～！
We've been saved!
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)
本当に あの化け物が死んだのか？
Is that monster really dead?
Nina, I'm proud to call you my apprentice.
おめぇは自慢の弟子だぜ ニーナ｡
How are you, Mom?
(ﾆｰﾅの声)
｢お母さん お元気ですか？➡
I'm still living in the capital.
私は今も
王都での生活を続けています｣｡
Nina!
≫(ﾊﾟﾝ屋)ニーナ！
持っていきな！
Take this!
The capital is busy with reconstruction.
(ﾆｰﾅの声)｢王都は
復興の工事で大忙しです｡➡
そちらは バハムートの被害が
あまりなかったと聞いて➡
I was so relieved to hear that your area
was not badly damaged by Bahamut.
とっても ほっとしています｣｡
A lot...
(ﾆｰﾅの声)｢あの日
いろんなことがありました｣｡
happened that day.
I don't think
(ﾆｰﾅの声)
｢きっと私は あの日のことを➡
I'll ever be able to forget what happened.
一生
忘れることはないと思います｣｡
Probably never.
(ﾆｰﾅの声)｢たぶん｣｡
The king became a hero that day
(ﾆｰﾅの声)｢英雄になった王様は➡
at the cost of his sight,
あの日以来
目が見えなくなってしまったけど➡
but he's still the king.
まだ 王様をやっています｣｡
(兵士たち)せいっ！
せいっ！ せいっ！ せいっ！
(ﾃﾞｨｱｽ)そこ～！ 気合いを入れろ！
(兵士たち)せいっ！
You there! Put your back into it!
Of course, the humans and the demons
here haven't put the past behind them
(ﾆｰﾅの声)
｢王都の人と悪魔さんたちは➡
当然 憎しみが消えて➡
and become great friends or anything.
仲よしというわけには
いかないけど➡
前みたいに
奴隷とかはなくなったので➡
But there aren't slaves like there used to be,
so their relationship is at least changing.
少しずつ 関係は
変化しているのかもしれません｡➡
ジャンヌさんは 王都を離れ➡
I hear that Jeanne left the capital,
and is currently living in the land of the gods.
今は
神の国で生活しているそうです｡➡
"Bright smiles for all"
When I go home to the village, I plan
to go see her on the elder's back.
里に帰ったら また
おばあちゃんの背中に乗って➡
会いに行くつもりです｣｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)ありがとう｡
Thank you.
The demon, Azazel...
(ﾆｰﾅの声)｢悪魔のアザゼルは…➡
Well, he went away somewhere.
どこかへ行ってしまいました｣｡
I'll be back to visit.
また来る｡
(ﾆｰﾅの声)
｢バッカスさんは変わらず➡
Bacchus is his same old self,
私を家族の一員として
優しく受け入れてくれています｣｡
still treating me like family.
Oh, young lady! Welcome home.
(ﾊﾝｻ)ああ～
お嬢さん おクワァえりなさい｡
Nina!
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)おっ ニーナ｡➡
How much longer are you planning
on crashing here anyway?
お前 一体
いつまで居座る気だ？ ああっ？
≫ドン(鍋を置く音)
≫(ﾘﾀ)こら！➡
Come on.
あんたたちも手伝いなさいよ｡
Why aren't any of you helping me?
(ﾆｰﾅの声)｢リタは あの日
大切な人を失ってしまったけど➡
Rita may have lost someone
very dear to her that day,
but she's back on her feet
and cooking me delicious meals.
今では すっかり立ち直り➡
私に おいしいご飯を
作ってくれています｣｡
(ﾊﾝｻ)お嬢さんの声➡
The young lady's voice...
It still hasn't returned.
やっぱり戻りませんねぇ｡
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)ああ｡➡
No. To think it would cost her her voice...
まさか 代償が声だとはな…｡
(ﾘﾀ)おらぁ！
(２人)うっ！
Hey, I told you to help me.
(ﾘﾀ)
手伝いなさいって言ってるでしょ｡
Yes, ma'am.
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ ﾊﾝｻ)は～い｡
-Time to eat!
(一同)いただきます｡
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)いただきま～す！
Thank you for the offer, but that's not necessary.
(ﾘﾄﾞ)ありがたいけど お構いなく｡
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)これは うまいな｡
This is quite delicious.
I can teach you how to make it if you'd like.
(ﾘﾀ)よかったら
作り方 伝授しましょうか？
-Are you sure?
-Yes.
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)いいのか？
(ﾘﾀ)ええ｡ 私の代わりに➡
You can make it for that drunk
and save me the trouble.
あの酔っ払いに作ってあげたら？
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)ぶふぅ～！
What's wrong with you?
(ﾘﾄﾞ)うっ！ ちょっと…｡
クゥ～ クゥ～！
Bacchus is in love with Sofiel.
(ﾆｰﾅの声)｢バッカスさんは
ソフィエルさんが好きです｣｡
クワァ～？
Lady Sofiel would never cook for such a fake god!
(ﾘﾄﾞ)
ソフィエル様が こんなエセ神に➡
料理など作るか！
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)誰がエセ神だ バカ野郎！
Who are you calling a fake god, you idiot?
パチパチ パチパチ
(ﾊﾝｻ)クワァ～ クゥ～！
And you guys cut it out too.
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)
おめぇらも はしゃぐんじゃねぇ｡
(ﾊﾝｻ)クワァ～ クワッ クワッ｡
ふふっ｡
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)
お… おめぇ 笑ってんじゃねぇ｡
Hey, this isn't funny.
I promise to introduce
these wonderful people to you one day.
(ﾆｰﾅの声)
｢いつか このすてきな人たちを➡
お母さんに紹介しますね｣｡
(ﾘﾄﾞ)今 なんと言った？
-What did you just say?
-Shut up!
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)だから ｢バカ野郎｣…｡
≪随分 盛り上がってるじゃねぇか｡
Seems like y'all are having fun here.
あら｡ あんたの分の料理は
作ってないわよ｡
Oh, I would have made more food
if I knew you were coming.
That's too bad.
そいつは残念だ｡
But I didn't come by to eat today.
だけど 今日は
飯を食いに来たわけじゃねぇんだ｡
I thought I'd get going soon.
そろそろ行こうと思ってな｡
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)そうか｡
おう｡
-I see.
-Yeah.
I've never liked the capital much anyway.
もともと 俺は
この王都って場所が苦手でよ｡
It's time I get back to my life of wandering.
放浪生活に戻ろうってな｡
つぅわけで 明日の朝には出る｡
So anyway, I'll be departing tomorrow morning.
元気でな｡
Take care of yourself.
あっ？ どうした？
ハグでもしてほしいのか？
What's up? You want a hug or something?
｢あのとき 会った｣｡
"I met her then."
はあ？ 誰に？
Met who?
｢バハムートの光の中で｣｡
"Inside Bahamut's light..."
"I met a woman."
｢女の人に｣｡
SHE WISHES...
YOU THE BEST.
Thanks, Nina.
ありがとな ニーナ｡
Nina, which way does the wind blow?
ニーナ 風は どっちに吹いてる？
Tomorrow!
Since coming to the capital,
there have been happy times,
(ﾆｰﾅの声)｢王都に来てから
うれしいこと 楽しいこと➡
fun times
and sad times where I cried.
悲しくて泣いてしまうこと➡
So much has happened,
いろんなことが
いっぱいあったけど➡
but, Mom, I'm still doing great!
お母さん
私は これからも元気です！｣｡
ニーナか｡
It's you, Nina.
ゴゴゴゴッ…
ドドォーン！
Bahamut isn't dead.
バハムートは死んじゃいねぇ｡
そうだろ？ アーミラ｡
Isn't that right, Amira?
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙの声)ファバロ～！
ん？
Favaro!
はあっ！
ヒヒィーン！(馬のいななき)
You'll see him again soon enough.
また すぐに会えるわよ｡
BAHASOUL!!
Baha Baha Baha Soul.
Thank you so much for watching!